so let's look at what a network on chip
might look like let's say we have some
sort of a square-ish tile that has a
core and maybe a level one cache and
such tiles normally will be connected to
a shared bus now let's say that these
four cores are using half of the
available trut on the bus because their
cash misses and coherence need to be
taken care of through the bus now let's
say we add another set of those cores
pretty much the same thing just
replicated now we have an even longer
thus possibly a slower bus that all
traffic from all these eight cores goes
to so we got a slower bus probably with
less throughput than the original small
one had yet it has twice the demand for
traffic so very quickly it will get
saturated now let's consider a type of
onchip network that is called a mesh so
here what we have is these core tiles
are individual
connected like this for example now
there is no more broadcast but this core
can still send a message to any other
core if we send a message to this this
is the link that gets used meanwhile
this core could be sending a message
here if we need to send a message from
here to here then these two links get
used meanwhile we can get these two
links used independently so as you can
see the total available throughput in
the entire network is several times the
throughput of this individual link link
and because it's a short link we can
have a very large throughput now I'm
going to take this 2x two mesh and copy
it so that I get four of those and
create a 4x4 mesh that now supports 16
cores twice as many as here note how
many new links are there now if we have
neighbor to neighbor communication we
can have these two talking these two
talking these two talking all over
independent links so as I increase the
number of cores I also increase the
number of these links naturally so that
the total trut available in this network
grows with the number of cores so the
number of cores grows the number of
links grows and that allows the
available through put to grow and that
means that I can have many more cores
than I could on the bus there are many
types of this so-called point to point
networks a mesh is one of those that is
very good for chip building because none
of these links intersect each other so
because chips are basically made by
printing things on Silicon it's
naturally good to have something that is
kind of flat like this and doesn't have
links going across different
nodes but we can build chips with some
amount of links Crossing each other and
thus we can have a mesh which is kind of
like what we have seen we can have have
a Taurus Network you build a Taurus by
taking the mesh and connecting the end
points to each other so the Taurus
really takes the link and kind of wraps
it around and then wraps it around and
so on and then you do that in the other
dimension tool you can think of these
processors as basically things on a
donut you would take this wrap it around
you get a cylinder then you take the end
points of the cylinder bend it and
create a d so that's why it's called a
Taurus but in reality what you really do
is you do this have a long link that
crosses here and a long link that
crosses here and so on and then you also
take this and create a long link that
goes here so that's how you create a
Taurus and then there are even fancier
networks that are still reasonably good
for on chip implementation such as
flattened butterfly if you're interested
in how this work a very good place to
start would be an advanced class on on
chip interconnects